## KINGLER BERCY

347 414-4170 kingler@me.com Portfolio: ww.kingler.me

#### **PROFILE**

I am a highly creative and multifaceted user experience designer, that approaches user interface design in a comprehensive way. I have extensive experience in creating detailed design documentation for building user-centered web applications within the financial industry and social media space. I can leverage web technologies like HTML, CSS, and jQuery libraries to prototype highly interactive web applications to empower stakeholders to make informed decisions about design concepts and to test usability.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER THRUDESIGNS STUDIO - CLIENT: IMAGINEER TECHNOLOGY GROUP / 10/2014 PRESENT

- Designed and prototyped a fund management dashboard and Investment portfolio application for one of ITG's flagship software applications called FundInsight. FundInsight is a web-based platform for managing the due diligence process associated with hedge funds management;
- Conducted user and stakeholder interviews and workshops to understand behaviors patterns, pain-points, and desired features prior to designing the interface;
- Organized features into meaningful categories for better workflow use case modeling;
- Conducted heuristic evaluations of FundInsight to identify possible enhancements or redesign opportunities;
- Created and presented wireframe mockups and customer journey maps to stakeholders for feedback and approval;
- Created a style guide with a full range of html elements for quickly prototyping future application module

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# USER EXPERIENCE ARCHITECT STANDARD AND POOR'S / 06/2013 - 04/2014

- Responsible for designing user centered internal web application for ratings analyst;
- Worked continuously with business analyst, developers, and QA staff to ensure the development of intuitive applications;
- Created style guides that defined global design patterns for 75 internal web applications;
- Conducted heuristic evaluations of legacy applications to identify possible enhancements or redesign opportunities;
- Organized usability testing with analyst and non analytical user;
- Created high level process flow diagrams that were presented and socialized with user groups and product managers;
- Created and presented both low and high fidelity wireframe mockups and storyboards to stakeholders for feedback approval;
- Participated in sprint planning and story estimation meetings;
- Worked with the business analyst on writing user stories and use cases scenarios;
- Worked on migrating 20 legacy internal applications to Liferay portal, which is an enterprise level CMS platform;

# E-COMMERCE PRODUCT MANAGER / UX ARCHITECT NYSE EURONEXT / 10/2011 - 04/2013

- Conducted requirement gathering workshops with stakeholders and end users for the global deployment of a e-commerce platform;
- Designed comprehensive information architectural documentation for six of NYSE's internal application/modules e-commerce portal: permission-ing system for both internal and external users, offer management and pricing rules system, discussion and collaboration tool, and a messaging framework;
- Presented UI wireframes to stakeholders, end users and developers during design meetings;
- Collaborated with other product managers on UX standards across all applications modules;
- Conducted weekly technical requirement meetings with the development team every sprint cycle;
- Conducted user acceptance testing with end users and stakeholders for final product acceptance.

# INFORMATION ARCHITECT / USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER MORGAN STANLEY SMITH BARNEY / CAPGEMINI NYC, NY / 3/2010 – 10/2011

- Researched and analyzed human task workflow procedures and real time processes of call center agents to determine design focus and content hierarchy;
- Created and successfully delivered information architect documentation; presenting tangible expression of strategy in the form of sketches, user flows diagrams, wireframes, and clickthrough PDF prototypes in high fidelity to simulate actual navigation;
- Collaborated with stakeholders and user groups, regularly, on design iterations;
- Create standardized CSS style sheets to control application layout consistency for both the Adobe LiveCycle Mosaic platform level and the individual Flex apps;
- Successfully delivered catalogs of Flex UI component with skin libraries to the development and integration teams tools: Omnigraffle, Illustrator, Flash Catalyst, Flex Builder;
- Created detailed use case documentation to help facilitate learning and understanding of application functionality, intent and flow for both developers and the customer service representative perspective;
- Conducted usability workshops to test design ideas

# INFORMATION ARCHITECT / USER INTERACTION DESIGNER INFONIC AG – NEW YORK, NY / 05/2011 – 08/2011

- Designed the user Interaction model for a securities pricing module for the next generation Hedgesphere software release. Hedgesphere is a sophisticated accounting software for hedge funds and fund of fund companies;
- Created high-fidelity click through wireframes storyboard to simulate the interaction model for the proposed workflow of fund analyst, fund administrators, and fund managers;
- Conducted design meetings and workshops with the user groups to capture business and usability requirements;
- Created Information Architect documentation, including wireframes, flow diagrams, component inheritance and dependency diagrams

### INFORMATION ARCHITECT EMBARC, LLC - HEMPSTEAD, NY / 4/2005 - 08/2010

- Designed the Information Architecture and User Experience for EMBARC's internal web-portal -Produce wireframes, site-maps, click through prototypes, and web design concepts of User Interface dashboards for account management use- Using prototyping tools like Omnigraffle and Visio;
- Successfully produced web design concepts, mockups, and wireframes for EMBARC's incubation enrollment process, which gathered input data and filtered them through a process

- of sequencing questions within predefined selection types to determine eligibility, resulting in faster approval cycles;
- Provided art direction and support for creating presentation and marketing materials for all new business pitches. With a focus on convey EMBARC's technology strategy solutions for CDFI's (Community Development Financial Institutions);
- Was responsible for maintaining a collaborative workflow environment with designers and developers through the uses of agile SDLC best practices;
- Research and collaborated with the R&D department for processes that would integrate
  existing business process management (BPM) ontologies with business incubation services
  and produce detailed strategy and implementation reports;

### **EDUCATION**

Virginia State University - Petersburg, VA - Major: Economics

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Platforms:  Desktop:  Web / CMS:	Mac OS, Linux, Windows Liferay, Drupal, Wordpress, Joomla, Magneto
Applications:	
Design:	Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Fireworks
	A
Prototyping:	Axure, Omnigraffle, Visio, Fireworks, HTML/CSS/JS
<b>5</b> , ,	
Development:	Brackets, Sublime Text, Dreamweaver, Eclipse
Code: Web:	HTML, XML, CSS, PHP JavaScript libraries (jqurey,
Code. Web.	angular js, node.js etc)